Curriculum Vitae

Virender Singh Bhandari

(Cost Accountant, ACMA)

Email: virender999@gmail.com

virender092004@yahoo.co.in

Mobile: 9818248590

Date of Birth: 21st Oct 1985

Address:

House No.28/288

Sector.44 Noida-201301

Objective: To serve common organizational goal and perform towards assigned responsibilities with ultimate

discipline, honesty, hard work and professional ethics.

Professional Summary:

Qualified CMA, having 08+ Years of strong experience in Accounts payable function, MIS reporting, Financial data analysis, Direct and Indirect Taxation, Accounts Receivable, Bank Reconciliation, employee travel reimbursements, and assistance in preparation of final accounts with sound knowledge of Indian GAAP.

ERP Experience: Excellent exposure in SAP FI (ECC 6.0), Tally 9.0 Platform.

Current Employer: Hindustan Powerprojects Pvt. Limited (Renewable energy Sector)

Designation: Assistant Manager- Finance & Accounts

Duration: Since July 01st, 2011 till date.

Key Deliverables:

- Independently responsible for handling end to end invoice processing in SAP FI Module
- Excellent command over SAP FI and sound knowledge of MS office.
- Invoice Processing on daily basis as per India GAAP and applicability of various taxes as per the law.
- Co-ordination with departments like HR/ Legal/ tax/ Treasury/ Admin for booking of expenses and provisions
- Booking of Prepaid and its amortization.
- Provide complete support to auditors in handling audits independently (Statutory/ Internal).
- Preparation of Variances in expenses for reporting to the management
- Handling of employee and vendor queries day in and out and providing timely resolution for end closure of the issues.
- Preparation of various dashboard and metrics from time to time as per the requirement from management like Monthly Cash flow MIS, O&M Expense Variance, GR/IR, Vendor advance reporting.
- Foreign Vendor remittance processing and organizing relevant documents.
- Assisting in preparation of Notes to financial statements,
- Performing testing in SAP for new process implementation or existing report configurations.

Previous Employer: Wipro Ltd. /Deputed at Client office: -- HPCL - Mittal Energy Ltd. (Oil refinery

Sector)

Designation: Sr. Accounts Officer

Duration: 1.8 Years

Key Deliverables:

Indirect Taxation:

- Maintaining Excise Reporting for Timely Booking of Payment in SAP.
- Quarterly / Annual Punjab VAT Return Filing.
- E Filing of Service Tax (ST-3) Return Filing.
- E Filing of Monthly ER-1 E Return
- Service Tax Payment of Foreign vendors under Reverse charge method, and Works Contract Payments.
- Preparation of TDS, VAT 28 WCT certificates
- Filing TDS Return.
- Preparation of Quarterly Dealer's Return.
- Handling internal audits and Statuary Audit queries.
- Assisting in preparation of reply to Notices and assessment order from Income Tax department.
- Vetting of Custom Duty levied invoices.

• Accounts & Finance, Audit functions:

- Vendor payments for Material & Services in SAP.
- o Vendor Account Scrutiny, MIS on Invoice pending, Vendor & GL account clearing,
- Payment Block Analysis.
 - o GR IR reconciliation, Analysis of Provisional Liability Account.
 - o Co-ordination with SAP team for development / Modification in SAP transaction,
- Creation of new GL A/c.

Past employer: Finasys Consultants (P) Ltd. (IT Consultancy Sector)

Designation: Executive Finance & Accounts

Duration: 1.5 Years Key Deliverables:

- Debtors Management
- Accounting for Invoice raised in the books of Group Company.
- Debtors Realisation & Reconciliation.
- Understanding & analysing business structure & working methodologies
- Requirement gathering for business changes in future.
- Implementation of financial Planning & Budgeting module.
- Bank reconciliation.

Past Experience:

Worked as an INDUSTRIAL TRAINEE in **BHEL** (**Bharat Heavy Electricals Ltd.**), a "navratna" PSU, New Delhi for 06 Months duration, in Finance & Accounts Dept.

Key Deliverables: Handling Voucher processing in Tally system and MIS reporting.

Profile Summary:

Total Experience	07+ Years	
Industry Exposure	Power, Engineering, Procurement & Constructions, Oil, Refining and	
	Petrochemicals, Manufacturing, and IT consultancy, BPO.	
ERP Skills	SAP FI (ECC 6.0), MS Office, Tally 9.0,	

Professional Qualification:-

ACMA – August 2008 pass out– 52.40 % – Institute of Cost & Management Accountants of India.

Academic Qualification:-

B.Com – 54.67 % - Feb 2007 – Shaheed Bhagat Singh College (Regular), Delhi University **HSSC (Commerce)** –72.25 % - March 2003, Kendriya Vidayalaya, CBSE

Experience:

Organisation	Designation	Duration
Hindustan Powerprojects	Assistant Manager- Finance &	July 01 st , 2011 till date
Pvt.Ltd.	Accounts	
Wipro (Deputed to HPCL MITTAL ENERGY LTD.)	Sr. Officer- Finance & Accounts	Nov'2009 to June'2011
Finasys Consultants Pvt. Ltd.	Executive- Finance & Accounts	Apr 2008- Oct'2009
BHEL (Bharat Heavy Electricals Ltd.) Navratna PSU.	Finance & Accounts Industrial Trainee	Apr 2007- Oct 2007

Personal Information:

Father's Name Late Shri Ranjeet Singh Bhandari

Date Of Birth 21.10.1985
Passport No. F7690381
Marital Status Single
Nationality Indian

Language Hindi, English